dress-for-less.com 2019-12-31

# Help at DFL

### Privacy Policy

### I. Contact

This policy applies to data processing by:

The Data Protection Officer of dress-for-less can be contacted at the following address  
Prof. Dr. Thomas Jäschke  
Data Tree AG  
Heubesstraße 10  
40597 Düsseldorf  
E-Mail: [office@datatree.eu](mailto:office@datatree.eu)  
Tel.: +49 211 93190-700  
Fax: +49 211 93190-799  

### II. Processing of personal data, type and purpose

#### 1\. Web hosting

The web host of this website is First Colo GmbH, Landstr. 291B, 60314 Frankfurt am Main (hereinafter referred to as "First Colo"). First Colo stores this website on its servers (hosting). A web hosting service is required for the offer on this website. The use of First Colo is carried out pursuant to point (f) of Article 6(1) p. 1 GDPR based on our legitimate commercial interest in providing our offer on this website.

In connection with the hosting, personal data that originates from the following actions by the user is processed by First Colo on our behalf:

  * visiting the website;
  * placing an order as a guest;
  * placing an order as an existing customer;
  * creating a customer account;
  * registering for the newsletter;
  * using the contact form.

We have concluded an order processing contract for hosting with First Colo. Through this contract, First Colo ensures that it processes data in accordance with the Data Protection Regulation and guarantees to protect the rights of the data subject. In particular, First Colo is certified in accordance with the reliable security standard ISO 27001:2013.

You can find further information about data protection in connection with First Colo [here](https://www.first-colo.net/).

#### 2\. When you visit our website

When you visit our website [https://www.dress-for-less.de](https://www.dress-for-less.de/) information will automatically be sent by the browser used on your device to our website's server. This information will be stored temporarily in a so-called log file. The following data will be stored and collected without any action on your part and deleted from the log files after 90 days:

  * IP address of the requesting computer,
  * Date and time of the request,
  * Name and URL of the file retrieved,
  * Website from which accessed (referrer URL),
  * Operating system of the accessing computer
  * Browser type and version and other information sent by the browser (such as your computer's operating system)
  * Performance and system data

This data processed by us for the following purposes:

  * to ensure smooth connection of the website,
  * to ensure our website is easy to use,
  * to analyse the system security and stability,
  * to detect and prevent attacks on our website,
  * to continually improve the website and
  * for other statistical and administrative purposes.

The legal basis for the data processing is provided by Art. 6 Para. 1 Clause 1 Letter f GDPR. Our legitimate interest is established by the purposes of data processing listed above.

In the event of an attack on our network infrastructure, your collected IP address will be analysed to assert or defend legal claims.

We also use cookies and analysis services when you visit our website. More details on this can be found under (Nos. IV and V) of this privacy policy.

#### 3\. Placing an order in our online shop

If you want to place an order for products on our website as a guest or as a registered customer, we process the following obligatory information:

  * title, first name, surname,
  * a valid email address,
  * invoice and delivery address
  * payment details (e.g. bank details) depending on the payment method you select

This data is processed,

  * in order to identify you as our contract partner;
  * to check the plausibility of the data entered;
  * to process the payment and delivery for your order;
  * where applicable, to personalise advertising measures;
  * to process any warranty claims and to assert any claims against you;

The data processing takes place upon your request and is necessary pursuant to Art. 6 Para. 1 Clause 1 Letter b and Letter f GDPR for the aforementioned purposes for the performance of a contract, to take steps prior to entering into a contract as well as our legitimate interests.

The personal data processed by us for the order will be stored until the end of the statutory warranty period and deleted automatically after this period, unless we have an obligation to store the data for a longer period pursuant to Article 6 Para. 1 Clause 1 Letter c GDPR due to retention periods and documentation obligations under tax and commercial law (German Commercial Code [HGB], German Criminal Code [StGB] or German Fiscal Code [AO]) or you have given consent to the data being stored for a longer period pursuant to Art. 6 Para. 1 Clause 1 Letter a GDPR.

#### 4\. Creating a customer account

We give you the option of creating a customer account with us. For the registration and the creation of the customer account, we need the following obligatory information:

  * title, first name, surname,
  * a valid email address
  * invoice and delivery address
  * password

In addition, you can give us further information voluntarily.

We process this data

  * to enable us to identify you as our customers;
  * to check the veracity of the data entered;
  * to personalise advertising measures;
  * to process any warranty claims and to assert any claims against you.

We collaborate with Emarsys eMarketing Systems AG Hans-Fischer-Straße 10, 80339 Munich (hereinafter referred to as "Emarsys") as a specialised provider for customer relation management relating to documentation, administration and marketing, to whom we send your data (email address, first name, surname, gender, purchasing history, postal address). This provider was carefully selected and commissioned by us, is bound by our instructions, and is monitored regularly with regard to the use of suitable technical and organisational measures relating to data security. Data is not transmitted to non-EEA states.

Data is processed at your request and is required pursuant to points (b) and (f) of Article 6(1) p. 1 GDPR for the purposes mentioned for the performance of the contract and for other pre-contractual measures, as well as for our legitimate interests.

The personal data processed by us for the order will be stored until expiry of the statutory warranty obligation and then automatically deleted, unless, pursuant to point (c) of Article 6(1) GDPR, we are obliged to store it for a longer period because of legal tax and commercial retention and documentation obligations (in accordance with the German Commercial Code (HGB), German Penal Code (StGB) or the German Tax:Code (AO), or you have consented to further storage pursuant to point (a) of Article 6(1) p. 1 GDPR.

#### 5\. In connection with our newsletters

As a customers or potential customer, we would like to send you our newsletters. Provided that you are not a customer of ours but still would like to receive our newsletter, we need your email address, as well as your title, first name and surname to send the newsletter so that we can address you personally. The newsletter is sent on the basis of your explicit consent (point (a) of Article 6(1) GDPR). Provided you are already a customer of ours, pursuant to point (f) of Article 6(1) p. 1 GDPR and our legitimate interests, we send you our newsletters to inform you about current product recommendations (direct marketing).

For the personalisation of the newsletter, we use the following specialised providers to whom we send the required personal data (email address) as well as data relating to your orders:

Emarsys eMarketing Systems AG  
Hans-Fischer-Straße 10,  
80339 Munich  
(hereinafter referred to as "Emarsys") 

By means of Emarsys, we can measure and analyse the behaviour of the recipients of our customer newsletter. This includes the opening, click, bounce, delivery, unsubscribe and delivery rate. The analysis is carried out using cookies or pixel tags, which collect information such as the IP address, browser type/version, email client and time of access. In this way, it is also possible to track who opens the email and clicks on the links contained within it. The analysis of user behaviour is carried out for the purpose of recognising reading habits and arranging content in accordance with this, and to measure and improve the success of email campaigns so that we can present you with relevant and targeted offers based on your interests. Data is not transmitted to states outside of the EEA.

You can opt out of the personalisation of our newsletter at any time by sending an email to us at [service@dress-for-less.de](mailto:service@dress-for-less.de). If you do so, we will not carry out any further personalisation, but will, if required, continue to send you our general newsletter.

In addition, it is possible to unsubscribe completely from our newsletters at any time, e.g. via a link at the end of each newsletter. Alternatively, you are also welcome to send your unsubscribe request at any time to [service@dress-for-less.de](mailto:service@dress-for-less.de) by email. The personal data that concerns you in this connection and exclusively for the purposes of sending the newsletter is deleted without undue delay after you have unsubscribed. However, we retain the fact that you have opted out and your email address to avoid inadvertently sending you newsletters in the future.

### III. Sharing data with third parties

In particular, insofar as it is legally permissible and is required for the fulfilment of the contractual relationships with you pursuant to point (b) of Article 6(1) p. 1 GDPR, we share your personal data with third parties.

#### 1\. Payment processing

We pass on payment details to payment service providers or credit institutions to carry out a payment process. As part of the performance of the contract, pursuant to point (b) of Article 6(1) GDPR, we use the payment service providers listed here to process payments:

  * SIX Payment Services GmbH, Langenhorner Chaussee 92-94, 22415 Hamburg
  * Klarna GmbH, Theresienhöhe 12, 80339 Munich
  * Sofort GmbH, Theresienhöhe 12, 80339 Munich
  * PayPal (Europe) S.à r.l. et Cie, S.C.A., 22-24 Boulevard Royal, L-2449 Luxembourg
  * Six Payments Services (Europe) S.A., 10, rue Gabriel Lippmann, L-5365 Munsbach
  * American Express Payment Services Limited, Belgrave House, 76 Buckingham Palace Road, London, SW1W 9AX, United Kingdom
  * American Express Payment Services Limited Postfach 11 01 01, 60036 Frankfurt

For processing, it may be necessary to forward the personal data collected during the payment process, such as name, address, telephone number, email address, debit/credit card or bank account details and transaction details to the payment service providers. The payment service providers collect some of this data themselves.

The shared data may be used by the third-party exclusively for the purposes mentioned.

#### 2\. For delivery of your order

In order to be able to ship your order in our shop (Art. 6 Para. 1 Clause 1 Letter b GDPR) and to pursue our legitimate interests of making the delivery as simple for you as possible (Art. 6 Para. 1 Clause 1 Letter f GDPR), we forward the data provided by you for the delivery address as well as your e-mail address and where applicable your telephone number to shipping service providers, which will despatch your consignment solely for the purpose of delivery and notification of delivery. These service providers are subject to the secrecy of communications.

#### 3\. For internal administrative and advertising purposes

We are a majority-owned company of SiGNA Retail GmbH and part of the company group [SIGNA Retail](https://www.signa.at/de/retail/).

As such, we sometimes show personal data (pseudonymous usage profiles) within a contractual relationship to

SIGNA Retail GmbH,  
Freyung 3,  
1010 Vienna  
(hereafter: "SIGNA") 

for analysis and marketing purposes (e.g. Google Analytics). The data is transferred on the basis of Art. 6 Para. 1 Clause 1 Letter f GDPR and to pursue our legitimate interests of a pseudonymous analysis of data by the SIGNA Sports Group.

You can object to the use of your personal data for advertising purposes as described under V. and VI. at any time without stating reasons. In this case SIGNA will also no longer be able to view your personal data.

#### 4\. For other purposes

We also disclose your personal data to third parties only if:

  * you have given your explicit consent pursuant to Art. 6 Para. 1 Clause 1 Letter a GDPR,
  * there is a statutory obligation to disclose pursuant to Art. 6 Para. 1 Clause 1 Letter c GDPR, and
  * the disclosure is necessary pursuant to Art. 6 Para. 1 Clause 1 Letter f GDPR to assert, exercise or defend legal claims and there is no reason to assume that you have an overriding legitimate interest in the non-disclosure of your data.

### IV. Cookies and pixel tags

#### 1\. What are cookies and pixel tags?

We use cookies on our website. These are small files which are automatically created by your browser and which are stored on your device (laptop, tablet, smartphone or the like) when you visit our website. Cookies do not damage your computer and do not contain viruses, Trojans or any other malware.

Information is stored in the cookie relating to the specific device used. This does not mean, though, that we can immediately establish your identity.

We use pixel tags (also called tracking pixels) in our online offering. Pixels are small graphics which are integrated using the HTML code of our webpage. The pixel tag does not store or change any information on your device, pixels also do not damage your device and do not contain viruses, Trojans or any other malware.

Pixels can send personal data such as your IP address, the referrer URL of the website visited, the time the pixel was viewed, the browser used and previously placed cookie information to a web server. As a result reach measurements and other statistical analyses which serve to optimise our offering can also be conducted.

The use of cookies makes it easier for you to use our website. We use for example so-called session cookies in order to recognise that you have already visited individual pages of our website, to recognise that you have already logged into your user account or to display the shopping basket. These are deleted automatically after you leave our site.

We also use temporary, so-called comfort cookies to optimise the user-friendliness of the website, which are stored on your device for a specific period of time. If you visit our website again in order to use our services, it automatically identifies that you have already visited us and what entries and settings you have made so that you do not have to input these again. These are usually deleted after a maximum of 30 days. Only those comfort cookies with language settings store these for 365 days.

We also use cookies and pixel tags in third-party tools in order to statistically record the use of our website and to analyse the use of our website for the purpose of optimising our offering for you (see under V). These analysis, tracking and targeting cookies allow us to automatically recognise that you have already visited us when you visit our website again. These cookies are deleted automatically after a defined period of time.

#### 2\. On which legal basis is the processing with the use of cookies and pixel tags based?

The data processed with the use of cookies and pixel tags is necessary for the aforementioned purposes to protect our legitimate interests in the analysis, optimisation and efficient operation of our website as well as the legitimate interests of third parties pursuant to Art. 6 Para. 1 Clause 1 Letter f GDPR.

#### 3\. What opt-out do you have?

Most browsers accept cookies and pixels automatically. However, you can configure your browser so that no cookies are stored on your computer or a notice always appears before a new cookie is created.

The complete deactivation of cookies may result, though, in you not being able to use all of the functions of our website. Instructions on how to turn off cookies in your browser can be found in the Help function of your browser or under the following links:

You can also use tools or browser add-ons to prevent the use of pixels on our website (e.g. the add-on "AdBlock").

Further opt-out options can be found in the information below on the tracking and targeting measures employed by us.

### V. Tracking und targeting

The tracking and targeting measures listed below are used by us on the basis of Art. 6 Para. 1 Clause 1 Letter f GDPR: With the use of these tracking measures, we want to ensure that our website is tailored to the needs of users and its continuous optimisation. We also use the tracking measures to statistically record the use of our website. By using these targeting measures, we want to ensure that you are only shown advertising tailored to your actual or presumed interests on your devices.

The respective data processing purposes and data categories can be found in the description of the tracking tools.

#### 1\. adrox

This website deploys the tool adrox of adrox GmbH, Niederstr. 1, 47829 Krefeld. A cookie is stored on your terminal device, which transfers pseudonymised information about purchased items. However, adrox does not receive any information with which users can be identified personally. The information gathered serves to create conversion statistics and thus create interest-oriented advertising on the websites of the contractual partners of adrox.

If you would like to opt-out of the deployment of the tool with effect for the future, you can also refuse the placement of the cookie required to do this through the setting in your browser which deactivates the automatic placement of cookies generally. We would point out, however, that in this instance not all functions of our website will be available in full.

#### 2\. Bing Conversion Tracking

We use Conversion Tracking from Microsoft Corporation, One Microsoft Way, Redmond, WA 98052-6399, USA. This allows us to track the activities of users on our website if they arrive at our website via Bing Ads advertisements.

If you arrive at our website via a Bing Ads advertisement, a cookie is placed on your computer. Here data on the use of the website is stored by Microsoft. This includes among other things the dwell time on the website, what areas of the website were accessed and via which advertisement you arrived at the website and, in the case of an order based on this, the order value and the time of the order. Information relating to your identity is not collected.

This information is sent to Microsoft servers in the USA, where it is stored for a maximum of 180 days. Microsoft complies with the data protection regulations of the US Privacy Shield and is registered with the US Privacy Shield programme of the US Department of Commerce. We have also concluded a contract data processing agreement with Microsoft for the use of Bing Ads. With this agreement Microsoft assures that it processes the data in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation and protects the rights of the data subject.

If you do not want to participate in the tracking process, you can also refuse to accept the placement of a cookie required for this purpose, for example by a browser setting which generally deactivates the automatic placement of cookies. Further information on data protection and the cookies used by Microsoft Bing can be found on [Microsoft's website](https://privacy.microsoft.com/de-de/privacystatement).

#### 3\. Criteo

On this website data is collected and stored for marketing and optimisation purposes with technologies of Criteo SA (32 Rue Blanche, 75009 Paris, France).

These technologies of Criteo allow the evaluation of our advertising campaigns and advertising content. This data can be used to create user profiles under a pseudonym. For this purpose cookies are used. The data collected using the Criteo technologies will not be used without separate consent being given by the data subject to identify personally the visitor to this website and not be combined with personal data about the bearer of the pseudonym. Criteo analyses the surfing behaviour using an algorithm and can then display targeted product recommendations as personalised advertising banners on other websites (so-called publishers). There is no other use of your data or disclosure to third parties. Further information on the technologies of Criteo can be found in [Criteo's privacy policy](https://www.criteo.com/de/privacy/).

Due to the use of Criteo, further pixels of contract partners with whom Criteo cooperates are loaded. An overview of all publishers and networks whose pixels are loaded can be found [here](http://www.criteo.com/de/privacy/criteo-works-with-the-following-platforms/).

You can object to this pseudonymous analysis of your surfing behaviour at any time. Click on the following [link](https://www.criteo.com/de/privacy) to Criteo to find instructions on how to deactivate the service of Criteo.

Please note that if you deactivate the display of personalised advertisements from Criteo and other advertising partners, you will continue to receive advertisements, but these will be less tailored to your interests/surfing behaviour.

#### 4\. Econda Web Analytics

To optimise the website and the databases in the background, we use the web analysis solutions of econda GmbH, Eisenlohrstr. 43, 76135 Karlsruhe.

In the procedures used, user profiles are created under a pseudonym. Cookies are used for this too. econda GmbH is entitled to use the quality seal "Tested Data Security" for the "Web Shop Controlling" area.

The data collected with the econda technology is not used to identify you personally and is not brought together directly with personal data via the bearer of the pseudonym without your special consent.

You can opt out of data processing by econda at any time with effect for the future by clicking [here](http://www.econda.de/econda/datenschutz/widerruf-datenspeicherung.html). If you click on the "Send" field, an opt-out cookie is placed by econda, with the effect that in future no visitor data from your browser is collected and stored by econda. The opt-out cookie is only valid in this browser and only for our website, and is placed on your device. If you delete the cookies in this browser, you will need to place the opt-out cookie again.

For further information, please visit <http://www.econda.de/>.

#### 5\. Emarsys Webextend

We use the cookie/pixel tag Webextend of Emarsys eMarketing Systems AG Hans-Fischer-Straße 10, 80339 Munich to produce newsletters tailored to your interests. To do this, we use available information, such as receipt and read confirmations from emails, information about computers and internet connections, operating system and platform, your internet history, your order history, date and time of the visit to the homepage, or products/items you have looked at. In principle, we use this information in a pseudonymised form, but also to send you newsletters related to your areas of interest, if required.

You can opt out of data processing by Emarsys Webextend by clicking [here](https://www.scarabresearch.com/privacy/). By clicking on the box under figure 6 (opt-out), an opt-out cookie is placed with the effect that in future no data about your usage behaviour on our website is collected and stored by Emarsys. The opt-out cookie is only valid in this browser and only for our website, and is placed on your device. If you delete the cookies in this browser, you will need to place the opt-out cookie again.

#### 6\. Facebook Custom Audiences

We use Facebook Website Custom Audiences of Facebook Ireland Limited (4 Grand Canal Square, Dublin 2, Ireland). This is a marketing service of Facebook. This enables us to show certain groups of pseudonymised visitors to our website, who also use Facebook, advertising on Facebook that is tailored individually to them and their interests.

A Facebook Custom Audience pixel tag is integrated into our website. This is a Java script code through which non-personal data about the use of the website is stored. This includes your IP address, the browser used and the access and target page. This information is transferred to Facebook servers in the US. Facebook is subject to the EU-US Privacy Shield, so that an appropriate level of data protection is guaranteed.

Whether you have stored a Facebook cookie is automatically checked. The Facebook cookie automatically determines whether you belong to the target group that is relevant to us. If you belong to the target group, appropriate advertisements are shown to you by Facebook. During this process, you are not identified personally by us or by Facebook through data comparison.

You can opt out of the use of the Custom Audiences service on the [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/ads/website_custom_audiences/) website. After logging in to your Facebook account, you can access the settings for Facebook ads.

You can obtain more information on data protection with Facebook from [Facebook's privacy policy guidelines](https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation).

If you do not have a Facebook account, you can opt out of the use of the service here.  
Enable Facebook tracking   
An opt-out cookie will be placed, which prevents the future collection of your data when visiting this website. The opt-out cookie is only valid in this browser and only for our website, and is placed on your device. If you delete the cookies in this browser, you will need to place the opt-out cookie again.

#### 7\. Google Analytics

We use Google Analytics on our website, a web analysis service of Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (hereafter: "Google"). In this connection, pseudonymised usage profiles are created and cookies (see under IV.1) are used. The information generated by the cookie on your use of this website such as the

  * browser type/version,
  * operating system used,
  * referrer URL (the previously visited page),
  * host name of the accessing computer (IP address),
  * time of the server request,

is sent to a Google server in the USA, where it is stored. Google complies with the data protection regulations of the US Privacy Shield and is registered with the US Privacy Shield programme of the US Department of Commerce.

We have also concluded a contract data processing agreement for the use of Google Analytics. With this agreement Google assures that it processes the data in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation and protects the rights of the data subject.

The information is used to analyse the use of the website, to compile reports on the website activities and to perform other services related to the use of the website and the internet for market research purposes and to ensure that these websites are tailored to the needs of users.

This information is also forwarded to third parties insofar as this is allowed by law or if third parties process this data on behalf of Google. Under no circumstances will your IP address be linked to other Google data. The IP addresses are anonymised, as a result they cannot be assigned to users (IP masking).

As an alternative to the [browser add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de), in particular with browsers on mobile devices, you can also prevent the collection of data by Google Analytics by clicking on this link. An opt-out cookie will be placed which will prevent your data from being collected when you visit this website in future. The opt-out cookie only applies to this browser and only to our website and is stored on your device. If you delete the cookies in this browser, you have to place the opt-out cookie again.

Further information on data protection relating to Google Analytics can be found in [Google Analytics Help](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=de).

In addition, we also use Google Optimize. This is a web analysis service of Google LLC, which is integrated into Google Analytics. Google Optimize enables us to carry out A/B and multivariate testing. In this way, we can find out which version of our website users prefer. You can find further information about this service here.

#### 8\. Google Adwords Conversion Tracking

We use Google Conversion Tracking on our website, a web analysis service of Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (hereafter: "Google") in order to statistically record the use of our website and for the purpose of optimising our offering for you. A cookie is placed by Google Adwords on your computer if you arrive at our website via a Google advertisement.

These cookies expire after 180 days. If the user visits certain pages of the website of the AdWords customer and the cookie has not yet expired, Google and the customer can tell that the user has clicked on the advertisement and been redirected to this page.

The information produced by the cookie on your use of this website is sent to a Google server in the USA, where it is stored. Google complies with the data protection regulations of the US Privacy Shield and is registered with the US Privacy Shield programme of the US Department of Commerce. We have also concluded a contract data processing agreement for the use of Google AdWords. With this agreement Google assures that it processes the data in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation and protects the rights of the data subject.

Every AdWords customer receives another cookie. Cookies can therefore not be tracked via the websites of AdWords customers. The information obtained with the conversion cookie is used to create conversion statistics for AdWords customers who have opted for Conversion Tracking. We learn the total number of users who have clicked on their advertisement and were redirected to a page with a conversion tracking tag. However, they do not obtain any information with which users can be personally identified.

If you do not want to participate in the tracking process, you can also refuse to accept the placement of a cookie required for this purpose, for example by a browser setting which generally deactivates the automatic placement of cookies. You can also deactivate cookies for conversion tracking by adjusting the settings in your browser so that cookies from the domain "www.googleadservices.com" are blocked.

Click [here](https://services.google.com/sitestats/de.html) for Google's privacy notice about conversion tracking.

#### 9\. Google Double Click

On our website information is collected and analysed to optimise the display of advertisements using cookies For this purpose we use targeting technologies of Google Inc. 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (Double Click, Double Click Exchange Buyer, Double Click Bid Manager). These technologies allow us to display advertisements tailored to your individual interests. The cookies used collect for example information about which of our products you have shown interest in. Based on the information, we can also show you on the websites of third parties offers which are tailored specifically to your interests, as revealed by your previous user behaviour. The collection and analysis of your user behaviour is only done pseudonymously and does not allow us to identify you. In particular, the information is not linked to personal data concerning yourself.

Google complies with the EU-US Privacy Shield, with the result that an adequate level of data protection is guaranteed.

The cookie will be deleted automatically after 30 days.

If you do not want to receive any advertising tailored to your interests, you can adjust this setting [here](http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/html/opt-out.html).

Further information and the data protection regulations relating to advertising and Google can be found in Google's privacy policy and terms of service.

#### 10\. Tradedoubler

This website participates in the partner programmes of Tradedoubler GmbH, Herzog-Wilhelm-Str. 26, 80331 Munich ("TradeDoubler"), a service for linking adverts in the form of text links, image links, advertising banners or input masks. TradeDoubler uses cookies, which are stored on your computer and which enable an analysis of the use of the website to be made. This allows information such as visitor traffic on these pages to be analysed.

The information produced by cookies and pixel tags on the use of this website and the delivery of advertising formats, is transferred to a TradeDoubler server and stored there. This information can be shared by TradeDoubler with contractual partners of TradeDoubler. However, TradeDoubler will not combine your IP address with other of your stored personal data.

You can opt out of data processing by TradeDoubler by clicking on this [link](http://publisher.tradedoubler.com/include/functions/optout.html) on the interface "No tracking please". An opt-out cookie will be placed, which prevents the future collection of your data when visiting this website. The opt-out cookie is only valid in this browser and only for our website, and is placed on your device. If you delete the cookies in this browser, you will need to place the opt-out cookie again.

Further information on the use of data can be obtained from the [privacy policy of TradeDoubler](https://www.tradedoubler.com/de/privacy-policy/).

#### 11\. RTB House

Our website uses technology from RTB House GmbH, Kurfürstendamm 226, 10719 Berlin, Germany, an affiliated company of RTB House S.A., 61/101 Złota Street, 00-819 Warsaw, Poland. This technology uses pixel tags and cookies to notify you of further content that may also be of interest you within our website or on third-party websites (retargeting). Pixel tags and cookies are used for this purpose. The recommendations integrated by RTB House are determined based on the content you have previously viewed. The content is automatically controlled and delivered by RTB House. The advertisement is displayed on a pseudonymous basis. The data stored in the cookie regarding your use of this website, such as cookie IDs, advertiser IDs, browser type/version, device information, referrer URL (the previously visited website) and time of the server request, as well as data relating to your activities (such as products or product category IDs visited by you) is transferred to an RTB House server in the EEA and stored there. Data will not be transmitted to third countries.

You can object to the processing of data by RTB House in order to display interest-based recommendations by clicking [here](https://www.rtbhouse.com/en/optout-page/). An opt-out cookie will be set, which prevents the future collection of your data when visiting this website. The opt-out cookie only applies to this browser and only for our website and will be stored on your device. If you delete the cookies in this browser, you will need to set the opt-out cookie again. Please note that you have to set the opt-out cookie in each device that you use to access our website separately. After making an objection, further interesting content will still be presented to you; however, this is no longer based on your previous usage behaviour on our website.

You can find more information on the RTB House privacy policy [here](https://www.rtbhouse.com/privacy-center/services-privacy-policy/).

#### 12\. Use of trbo

Our website uses technology from trbo GmbH, Leopoldstraße 41, 80802 Munich, Germany. With the help of this technology, data about the browsing behaviour of website visitors is collected and stored on a pseudonymous basis for marketing purposes. This data is saved on your computer with the help of “cookie” text files (see section 4 IV.1 for a description of the function of cookies/pixels and the data they collect). The cookies collect data such as the categories that you have visited, the products that you have viewed or information on which articles you have placed in your shopping basket. Using an algorithm, trbo analyses browsing behaviour so that you are shown personalised advertisements on our website including targeted product recommendations or promotions specific to your interests and your browsing behaviour. Under no circumstances can this data be used to identify visitors to this website. The data is not used for any other purpose or passed on to third parties.

You can object to the pseudonymous analysis of your browsing behaviour on this website. By clicking on the following link for opting out <https://www.trbo.com/opt-out/> and clicking the “opt-out” button, a new cookie (an opt-out cookie) will be placed in your browser. This cookie lets trbo know that no data about your usage behaviour can be collected and processed. You have the option to reactivate this function. This setting has to be changed in each browser separately. If you have set your browser to not allow any cookies, this also applies to the opt-out cookie.

You can find more information about the technology from trbo in the trbo [privacy policy](https://www.trbo.com/datenschutz/).

### VI. Data subject rights

You have the right:

  * pursuant to Art. 7 Para. 3 GDPR to withdraw your consent from us at any time. As a result, we will in future no longer be allowed to continue the data processing based on this consent;
  * pursuant to Art. 15 GDPR to ask for information about your personal data processed by us. In particular you can ask for information about the processing purposes, the category of personal data, the categories of recipients to whom your data has been or will be disclosed, the planned storage period, the existence of a right to correction, deletion, restriction of processing or objection, the existence of a right to complain, the origin of your data, if this was not collected by us, and about the existence of automated decision-making including profiling and if applicable meaningful information about its details;
  * pursuant to Art. 16 GDPR to ask for the immediate rectification of inaccurate or immediate completion of incomplete personal data stored by us;
  * pursuant to Art. 17 GDPR to ask for the erasure of your data stored by us, unless the processing is necessary to exercise the right of freedom of expression and information, to meet a legal obligation, for reasons of public interest or to assert, exercise or defend legal claims;
  * pursuant to Art. 18 GDPR to ask for the restriction of the processing of your personal data, if the accuracy of the personal data is contested by you, the processing is unlawful and you oppose its erasure and we no longer need the data, but it is required to assert, exercise or defend legal claims or you have objected to the processing pursuant to Article 21 GDPR;
  * pursuant to Art. 20 GDPR to ask to receive your personal data which you have provided us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format or transmit it to another controller and
  * pursuant to Art. 77 GDPR to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority. As a rule you can contact for this purpose the supervisory authority for your habitual residence, place of work or our headquarters.

In order to exercise your data subject rights against us, please contact [datenschutz@dress-for-less.de](mailto:datenschutz@dress-for-less.de)

### VII. Right to object

If your personal data is processed on the basis of legitimate interests pursuant to Art. 6 Para. 1 Clause 1 Letter f GDPR, you have the right, pursuant to Art. 21 GDPR, to object to the processing of your personal data if there are grounds relating to your particular situation or you object to direct marketing. In the latter case you have a general right to object which will be acted upon by us without you needing to state grounds relating to your particular situation.

If you would like to exercise your right to object, you need only send an e-mail to [datenschutz@dress-for-less.de](mailto:datenschutz@dress-for-less.de)

### VIII. Data security

All data transmitted personally by you is transmitted in encrypted form with the customary secure standard TLS (Transport Layer Security). TLS is a secure and tested standard which is also used in online banking. You can recognise a secure TLS connection by among other things the s after http (i.e. https://..) in your browser's address bar or by the padlock symbol at the top of your browser.

We also use suitable technical and organisational security measures to protect your data against accidental or deliberate manipulation, partial or complete loss, destruction or unauthorised access by third parties. Our security measures are improved continuously in line with technological developments.

### IX. Date of and amendments to this privacy policy

This data protection declaration is current as at May 2018.

Due to the development of our website, offers via the website or changes in statutory or regulatory requirements, it may be necessary to amend this data protection declaration. The current data protection declaration as amended can be downloaded at any time from the website [https://www.dress-for-less.com/help#Privacy policy](https://www.dress-for-less.com/help#Privacy%20policy) and printed out.
